Behdad Keynejad

iOS Developer

Tehran, Iran behdaad.me behdad.keynejad@gmail.com

I am looking to transition back to being a software engineer following 3+ years of technical leadership at a large scale company with more than 40 million users. Although I enjoy leading and growing teams, I prefer being more hands-on on a day-to-day basis.

Work Experience

iOS Tech Lead Snapp! Mar 2018—Present

Tehran, Iran

- Created a **scalable app architecture** using **protocol-oriented** programming and Clean Architecture principles after studying app architectures such as VIPER, Uber RIBs, MVVM and Clean Swift. (<u>Link</u>)
- Initiated, planned and worked on the project of **migration** of legacy code of Passenger app from Objective-C and MVC to **Swift** and the new architecture. (<u>Link</u>)
- Led the **rewrite** project of the Driver app from Objective-C and MVC to Swift, based on an overhaul of the application from design and usability standpoints. (<u>Link</u>)
- **Designed and architected** the technical part of many impactful features across both Passenger and Driver apps such as Chat, Change Destination, and the switch to being a super app offering multiple services.
- Standardized development workflow by creating a Git branching model, introducing code review processes and using SwiftLint and Danger. (<u>Link</u>)
- Automated release process using Xcode Server and GitLab CI/CD which decreased QA lead time by 1 hour. (Link)
- Automated writing mocks and stubs boilerplate code for unit tests by roughly 80% using SwiftyMocky.
- Enabled product-based team structure by setting up **release train** processes so teams could work on the same code base independently resulting in smaller and regular releases every two weeks.
- Cared for accessibility of the Passenger app by implementing VoiceOver support.
- Built and led a team of 12 after scaling up from 3 by interviewing 100+ candidates.
- Mentored less experienced employees in both engineering and leadership career paths.
- Played an active role in growing the engineering team from 20 to 300+ by making hiring plans based on **OKRs**.
- Spearheaded the effort on **diversity and inclusion** by hiring the first female developer in the engineering team.

iOS Developer Snapp! May 2017—Feb 2018

Tehran, Iran

- Added support for multiple map tile providers by wrapping implementations in a protocol.
- Architected the map framework which was later used in both Passenger and Driver apps.
- Adapted all the custom views of the app to Safe Area after the launch of iPhone X. (<u>Link</u>)
- Designed the API for our in-house network module called. (Link)
- Unified coding style in the team by writing a Swift style guide. (<u>Link</u>)
- Added support for Multitasking on iPad.

iOS Developer Lyan 2016–2017

Tehran, Iran

Developed an app for business owners of an e-commerce platform.

iOS Developer Freitag & Co. GmbH Summer 2016

Frankfurt, Germany

A summer internship program during which I developed an office management app.

iOS Developer Nazdiktarinha 2015–2016

Tehran, Iran

• Developed an app showing nearby points of interest, events and venues.

Education

• **B.Sc. Computer Engineering,** Sharif University of Technology, Tehran.

2011-2017

Languages and Technologies

Languages: Swift, Objective-C, Python3, JavaScript

Technologies: UIKit, Auto Layout, SwiftUI, Combine, Xcode Server
Other: iOS App Architecture, GitLab CI/CD, Git, Code Signing

Projects

• **iOS-App-Signer** is a fork of a project with the same name which I modified to accommodate our team needs in Snapp!. (<u>Link</u>)

• **SNPArchitecture** is a scalable iOS app architecture used for iOS apps in Snapp! based on VIPER, RIBs and Clean Swift. (Link)

Writing

- A post on why we decided to rewrite the Passenger app in Snapp! and the challenges we faced during the rewrite process. (<u>Link</u>)
- A post about productivity and mental health in Farsi. (Link)

Interests

Apple and technology in general.

- Playing racket sports (Tennis, Padel, Squash) and watching Formula 1.
- You can find me on the internet using the regular expression behda+d: behda{2}d@GitHub | behda{2}d@LinkedIn | behda{1}d@Medium | behda{1}d@StackExchange | behda{3}d@Twitter | behda{8}d@Instagram.